# William Rossen

 Poston, MA, USA
 ■ wor101@gmail.com
 ★ https://willrossen.com
 ♠ wor101

#### **Profile**

I am a full-stack Software Engineer currently based in Boston, MA. Most recently, I co-created Chimera, an open-source tool for automating canary deployments of containerized microservices. I am experienced in JavaScript, Node.js, React, Ruby, PostgreSQL, Docker, and a variety of AWS services.

# **Professional Experience**

## **Co-Creator, Software Engineer,** *Chimera* □

2022 – present

Designed, prototyped and implemented Chimera (https://chimera-deploy.dev), an open-source tool for performing automated canary deployments of containerized microservices.

- Led implementation of AWS SDK to automate creation and teardown of multiple AWS services
- Implemented an Express backend to query and coordinate custom AWS resources
- Created multiple containerized microservices communicating via a service mesh for development testing
- Utilized AWS CloudWatch and Prometheus to monitor metrics related to deployment
- Automated failed deployment rollback process based off of production metrics
- Configured server-sent events stream for sending time-based metrics data and status to user interface
- Dockerized Chimera for simple execution in both local and remote environments
- Co-presented a live tech talk on Chimera's development and usage
- Designed detailed infrastructure diagrams and co-authored a comprehensive case study

#### Full-Stack Web Developer, Self-Employed

2020 - 2022

- Requestotron: A Requestbin-like app for debugging HTTP requests
  - DigitalOcean VPS Hosted, NGINX reverse proxy, NodeJS, Express, PostgreSQL
- Mello: A Trello-like app for task management
  - NodeJS, React, Redux, MongoDB
- CoreSpace: A game aid for the tabletop miniatures game
  - Ruby, Sinatra, Minitest
- NPC Tracker: An app for tracking character interactions in RPGs
  - Ruby, Sinatra, PostgreSQL, BCrypt

#### **Account Services Specialist,** Ceva Logistics

2010 - 2021

• Developed strong relationships with key customer contacts, serving as the primary point of contact for customer support, account management matters and improvement opportunities

#### Skills

Languages	Frameworks	Misc Tech	Cloud Tech
Ruby, JavaScript, Go,	Node.js, React, Redux,	Git, Github, Linux,	EC2, ECS, ECR, App
SQL, HTML, CSS	Express, Sinatra,	HTTP, NGINX, RESTful	Mesh, Fargate, S3,
	jQuery, Tailwind	API, PostgreSQL,	CloudWatch,
		MongoDB	DigitalOcean, Heroku

## Education

Launch School, Software Engineering												
_		_			e.					_		

2020 - 2022

A multi-year, full-stack software engineering curriculum focused on mastery-based learning.

**Penn State,** BS in Criminal Justice

2001 - 2005